<resources>
    <string name="app_name">RAMADAN</string>
    <string-array name="ramadan_reslst">
        <item>allah</item>
        <item>alhamdu lillah</item>
        <item>alam</item>
        <item>akber</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="ramadan_description">
        <item>amin</item>
        <item>rahim</item>
        <item>gofur </item>
        <item>karim</item>

    </string-array>

    <string name="rj_niat">
       রোজার নিয়ত:\n

نَوَيْتُ اَنْ اُصُوْمَ غَدًا مِّنْ شَهْرِ رَمْضَانَ\n
        الْمُبَارَكِ فَرْضَا لَكَيَا اللهُ فَتَقَبَّل مِنِّى\n
      اِنَّكَ اَنْتَ السَّمِيْعُ الْعَلِيْم\n

আরবি নিয়ত :\n
        নাওয়াইতু আন আছুম্মা গাদাম মিন শাহরি রমাজানাল মুবারাকি ফারদাল্লাকা,\n
        ইয়া আল্লাহু ফাতাকাব্বাল মিন্নি ইন্নিকা আনতাস সামিউল আলিম।,\n
    </string>
    <string name="ifter_dowa">
   ইফতারের সময় এই দোয়া পড়ে ইফতার করা:\n\n

اَللَّهُمَّ لَكَ صُمْتُ وَ عَلَى رِزْقِكَ وَ\n
        اَفْطَرْتُ بِرَحْمَتِكَ يَا اَرْحَمَ الرَّاحِيْمِيْن\n

উচ্চারণ :\n
        আল্লাহুম্মা লাকা ছুমতু ওয়া আলা রিযক্বিকা\n
        ওয়া আফতারতু বিরাহমাতিকা ইয়া আরহামার রাহিমিন।\n

    </string>
    <string name="rojar_foroj">
        রোজার ৩ ফরজ : \n\n

১. নিয়ত করা\n
২. সব ধরনের পানাহার থেকে বিরত থাকা\n
৩. যৌন আচরণ থেকে বিরত থাকা।\n

আবার অন্যভাবে বলা যায়\n
        রোজার ফরজ ৬০ টি তা হলো,৩০ রোজার ৩০ নিয়ত করা ফরজ \n এবং ৩০ টি রোজা রাখা ও ফরজ।এভাবে বললে ফরজ হয় ৬০ টি।\n
    </string>
    <string name="rojer_wajib">
        রমজানের ওয়াজিবসমূহ

রমজানের সঙ্গে সম্পৃক্ত ওয়াজিব দুটি।\n
        যথা: সদকাতুল ফিতর আদায় করা \n
        ও ঈদের নামাজ পড়া। \n
        ঈদের দিন সকালে যিনি নিসাব পরিমাণ সম্পদের মালিক বা অধিকারী থাকবেন,\n
        তিনি তাঁর নিজের ও পরিবারের সব সদস্যের ফিতরা আদায় করবেন।\n
        যদি কেউ নিসাব পরিমাণ সম্পদের মালিক না–ও থাকেন,\n
        তবু সুন্নত বা নফল হিসেবে হলেও সদকাতুল ফিতরা প্রদান করা উত্তম।\n

    </string>
    <string name="fajael">
        ১. এ মাসের সাথে ইসলামের একটি গুরুত্বপূর্ণ রুকনের সম্পর্ক রয়েছে ; আর তা হলে সিয়াম পালন।\n
হজ যেমন জিলহজ মাসের সাথে সম্পর্কিত হওয়ার কারণে সে মাসের মর্যাদা বৃদ্ধি করেছে এমনি সিয়াম রমজান\n
 মাসে হওয়ার কারণে এ মাসের মর্যাদা বেড়ে গেছে।\n
 আল্লাহ রাব্বুল আলামিন বলেন : হে মোমিনগণ! তোমাদের উপর সিয়াম ফরজ করা হয়েছে, যেমনি ফরজ করা \n
হয়েছে তোমাদের পূর্ববর্তীদের উপর-যাতে তোমরা মুত্তাকি হতে পার।\n
 [সূরা বাকারা : ১৮৩] রাসূলে করিম সাল্লাল্লাহু আলাইহি ওয়া সাল্লাম বলেছেন : ইসলাম যে পাঁচটি ভিত্তির উপর প্রতিষ্ঠিত তার\n
 একটি হল সিয়াম পালন। এ সিয়াম জান্নাত লাভের একটি মাধ্যম ; যেমন হাদিসে এসেছে : যে আল্লাহ ও তাঁর রাসূলের প্রতি ঈমান\n
 আনল, সালাত কায়েম করল, জাকাত আদায় করল, সিয়াম পালন করল রমজান মাসে, আল্লাহ তাআলার কর্তব্য হল তাকে জান্নাতে\n
 প্রবেশ করানো। [ বোখারি ] ২. রমজান হল কোরআন নাজিলের মাস। আল্লাহ রাব্বুল আলামিন বলেন : রমজান মাস,\n
 এতে নাজিল হয়েছে আল-কোরআন, যা মানুষের দিশারি এবং স্পষ্ট নিদর্শন ও সত্যাসত্যের পার্থক্যকারী।\n
[ সূরা বাকারা : ১৮৪ ] রমজান মাসে সপ্তম আকাশের লওহে মাহফুজ থেকে দুনিয়ার আকাশে বায়তুল ইজ্জতে \n
পবিত্র আল-কোরআন একবারে নাজিল হয়েছে। সেখান হতে আবার রমজান মাসে অল্প অল্প করে নবী করিম সাল্লাল্লাহু\n
 আলাইহি ওয়া সাল্লাম-এর প্রতি নাজিল হতে শুরু করে। কোরআন নাজিলের দুটি স্তরই রমজান মাসকে ধন্য করেছে। \n
শুধু আল-কোরআনই নয় বরং ইবরাহিম আ.-এর সহিফা, তাওরাত, যবুর, ইঞ্জিল সহ সকল ঐশী গ্রন্থ এ মাসে অবতীর্ণ\n
 হয়েছে বলে তাবরানী বর্ণিত একটি সহি হাদিসে উল্লেখ করা হয়েছে। (সহি আল-জামে) এ মাসে মানুষের হেদায়াত ও\n
 আলোকবর্তিকা যেমন নাজিল হয়েছে তেমনি আল্লাহর রহমত হিসেবে এসেছে সিয়াম। তাই এ দুই নিয়ামতের শুকরিয়া \n
আদায় করতে বেশি বেশি করে কোরআন তিলাওয়াত করা উচিত। প্রতি বছর রমজান মাসে জিবরাইল রাসূলুল্লাহ সাল্লাল্লাহু\n
 আলাইহি ওয়া সাল্লাম-কে পূর্ণ কোরআন শোনাতেন এবং রাসূল সাল্লাল্লাহু আলাইহি ওয়া সাল্লাম-ও তাকে পূর্ণ কোরআন শোনাতেন। \n
আর জীবনের শেষ রমজানে আল্লাহর রাসূল দু বার পূর্ণ কোরআন তিলাওয়াত করেছেন। সহি মুসলিমের হাদিস দ্বারা এটা প্রমাণিত।\n
    </string>
    <string name="title_activity_ramadan_doa">RamadanDoa</string>

    <string name="large_text">
        "Material is the metaphor.\n\n"

        "A material metaphor is the unifying theory of a rationalized space and a system of motion."
        "The material is grounded in tactile reality, inspired by the study of paper and ink, yet "
        "technologically advanced and open to imagination and magic.\n"
        "Surfaces and edges of the material provide visual cues that are grounded in reality. The "
        "use of familiar tactile attributes helps users quickly understand affordances. Yet the "
        "flexibility of the material creates new affordances that supercede those in the physical "
        "world, without breaking the rules of physics.\n"
        "The fundamentals of light, surface, and movement are key to conveying how objects move, "
        "interact, and exist in space and in relation to each other. Realistic lighting shows "
        "seams, divides space, and indicates moving parts.\n\n"

        "Bold, graphic, intentional.\n\n"

        "The foundational elements of print based design typography, grids, space, scale, color, "
        "and use of imagery guide visual treatments. These elements do far more than please the "
        "eye. They create hierarchy, meaning, and focus. Deliberate color choices, edge to edge "
        "imagery, large scale typography, and intentional white space create a bold and graphic "
        "interface that immerse the user in the experience.\n"
        "An emphasis on user actions makes core functionality immediately apparent and provides "
        "waypoints for the user.\n\n"

        "Motion provides meaning.\n\n"

        "Motion respects and reinforces the user as the prime mover. Primary user actions are "
        "inflection points that initiate motion, transforming the whole design.\n"
        "All action takes place in a single environment. Objects are presented to the user without "
        "breaking the continuity of experience even as they transform and reorganize.\n"
        "Motion is meaningful and appropriate, serving to focus attention and maintain continuity. "
        "Feedback is subtle yet clear. Transitions are efﬁcient yet coherent.\n\n"

        "3D world.\n\n"

        "The material environment is a 3D space, which means all objects have x, y, and z "
        "dimensions. The z-axis is perpendicularly aligned to the plane of the display, with the "
        "positive z-axis extending towards the viewer. Every sheet of material occupies a single "
        "position along the z-axis and has a standard 1dp thickness.\n"
        "On the web, the z-axis is used for layering and not for perspective. The 3D world is "
        "emulated by manipulating the y-axis.\n\n"

        "Light and shadow.\n\n"

        "Within the material environment, virtual lights illuminate the scene. Key lights create "
        "directional shadows, while ambient light creates soft shadows from all angles.\n"
        "Shadows in the material environment are cast by these two light sources. In Android "
        "development, shadows occur when light sources are blocked by sheets of material at "
        "various positions along the z-axis. On the web, shadows are depicted by manipulating the "
        "y-axis only. The following example shows the card with a height of 6dp.\n\n"

        "Resting elevation.\n\n"

        "All material objects, regardless of size, have a resting elevation, or default elevation "
        "that does not change. If an object changes elevation, it should return to its resting "
        "elevation as soon as possible.\n\n"

        "Component elevations.\n\n"

        "The resting elevation for a component type is consistent across apps (e.g., FAB elevation "
        "does not vary from 6dp in one app to 16dp in another app).\n"
        "Components may have different resting elevations across platforms, depending on the depth "
        "of the environment (e.g., TV has a greater depth than mobile or desktop).\n\n"

        "Responsive elevation and dynamic elevation offsets.\n\n"

        "Some component types have responsive elevation, meaning they change elevation in response "
        "to user input (e.g., normal, focused, and pressed) or system events. These elevation "
        "changes are consistently implemented using dynamic elevation offsets.\n"
        "Dynamic elevation offsets are the goal elevation that a component moves towards, relative "
        "to the component’s resting state. They ensure that elevation changes are consistent "
        "across actions and component types. For example, all components that lift on press have "
        "the same elevation change relative to their resting elevation.\n"
        "Once the input event is completed or cancelled, the component will return to its resting "
        "elevation.\n\n"

        "Avoiding elevation interference.\n\n"

        "Components with responsive elevations may encounter other components as they move between "
        "their resting elevations and dynamic elevation offsets. Because material cannot pass "
        "through other material, components avoid interfering with one another any number of ways, "
        "whether on a per component basis or using the entire app layout.\n"
        "On a component level, components can move or be removed before they cause interference. "
        "For example, a floating action button (FAB) can disappear or move off screen before a "
        "user picks up a card, or it can move if a snackbar appears.\n"
        "On the layout level, design your app layout to minimize opportunities for interference. "
        "For example, position the FAB to one side of stream of a cards so the FAB won’t interfere "
        "when a user tries to pick up one of cards.\n\n"
    </string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>


    <string name="title_activity_kalima_page1">kalima_page1</string>


    <string name="kalimapart1">

            "لآ اِلَهَ اِلّا اللّهُ مُحَمَّدٌ رَسُوُلالل\n"


    </string>
    <string name="kalimapart2">

 "There is none worthy of worship except Allah and Muhammad is the Messenger of Allah.\n"
    </string>
    <string name="kalimapart3">

        "Laaa Ilaaha Illa-llaahu Muhammadur- Rasoolu-llaah\n"

    </string>

    <string name="kalimapart4">
        "/اَشْهَدُ اَنْ لَّآ اِلٰهَ اِلَّا اللهُ وَحْدَہٗ لَاشَرِيْكَ لَہٗ وَاَشْهَدُ اَنَّ مُحَمَّدًا عَبْدُهٗ وَرَسُولُہٗ‎"
    </string>

    <string name="Kalimapart5">
       "Bear witness that there is none worthy of worship except Allah,"
        "the One alone, without partner, and I bear witness that Muhammad is His servant and Messenger"
    </string>

    <string name="Kalimapart6">
        "Ash-hadu Al-laaa Ilaaha Illa-llaahu Wahdahoo Laa Shareeka Lahoo"
        "Wa-Ash-hadu Anna Muhammadan ‘Abduhoo Wa Rasooluhu."


    </string>
    <string name="kalimapart7">
        "سُبْحَان اللهِ وَالْحَمْدُلِلّهِ وَلا إِلهَ إِلّااللّهُ وَاللّهُ أكْبَرُ وَلا حَوْلَ وَلاَ قُوَّةَ إِلَّا بِاللّهِ الْعَلِيِّ الْعَظِيْم‎"

    </string>

    <string name="Kalimapart8">
        "Glory be to Allah and all praise be to Allah, there is none worthy of worship except Allah, and Allah is the Greatest.\n"
        "There is no might or power except from Allah, the Exalted, the Great One.\n"

    </string>

    <string name="kalimapart9">
        "Subhaana-llaahi Walhamdu Lillaahi Walaaa Ilaaha Illa-llaahu Wallaahu Akbar.\n"
        "Walaa Hawla Walaa Quwwata Illaa Billaahi-l ‘Aliyyil ‘Azeem\n"
    </string>

    <string name="Kalimapart10">
        "لَآ اِلٰهَ اِلَّا اللهُ وَحْدَهٗ لَا شَرِيْكَ لَهٗ لَهُ الْمُلْكُ وَ لَهُ"
        "الْحَمْدُ يُحْىٖ وَ يُمِيْتُ وَ هُوَحَیٌّ لَّا يَمُوْتُ اَبَدًا اَبَدًاؕ ذُو"
        "الْجَلَالِ وَالْاِكْرَامِؕ بِيَدِهِ الْخَيْرُؕ وَهُوَ عَلٰى كُلِّ شیْ ٍٔ قَدِیْر"ٌؕ"

    </string>

    <string name="Kalimapart11">
        "There is none worthy of worship except Allah. He is alone and has no partner.\n"
        To Him belongs the Kingdom and for Him is all praise. He gives life and causes death.\n"
        In His hand is all good and He has power over everything.\n"

    </string>

    <string name="Kalimapart12">
        "Laaa Ilaaha Illa-llaahu Wahdahoo Laa Shareeka-lahoo Lahu Mulku Walahu\n"
        Hamdu Yuhyee Wayumeetu Wahuwa Hayyu Laa Yamootu Abadan Abada.\n"
        Dhu Jalaali Wal Ikraam. Biyadihil Khair. Wahuwa Alaa Kulli Shai-’in Qadeer.\n"

    </string>
    <string name="Kalimapart13">

"اَللّٰهُمَّ اِنِّیْٓ اَعُوْذُ بِكَ مِنْ اَنْ اُشْرِكَ بِكَ شَيْئًا وَّاَنَآ اَعْلَمُ بِهٖ وَ اَسْتَغْفِرُكَ لِمَا لَآ"
        "اَعْلَمُ بِهٖ تُبْتُ عَنْهُ وَ تَبَرَّأْتُ مِنَ الْكُفْرِ وَ الشِّرْكِ وَ الْكِذْبِ وَ الْغِيْبَةِ وَ الْبِدْعَةِ وَ النَّمِيْمَةِ وَ الْفَوَاحِشِ و"َ
        "الْبُهْتَانِ وَ الْمَعَاصِىْ كُلِِّهَا وَ اَسْلَمْتُ وَ اَقُوْلُ لَآ اِلٰهَ اِلَّا اللهُ مُحَمَّدٌ رَّسُوْلُ الله"ِؕ

    </string>
    <string name="Kalimapart14">
        "O Allah! I seek refuge in You from that I should ascribe any partner with You knowingly.\n"
        "I seek Your forgiveness for the sin of which I have no knowledge.\n"
        "lying and backbiting, innovation and slander,\n"
        "lewdness and abomination and all other acts of disobedience,\n"
        "I submit to Your will.I believe and I declare that there is none worthy of\n"
        "worship except Allah and Muhammad is the Messenger of Allah.\n"
    </string>
    <string name="Kalimapart15">
        "Allaa-humma Inneee A’udhu-bika Min An Ushrika Bika Shay-awn Wa-ana A’lamu Bihee Wa-\n"
        "astaghfiruka Limaa Laaa A’lamu Bihee Tubtu ‘Anhu Wata-barraatu Mina-l Kufri Wash-shirki Wal-kidhbi\n"
        "Wal-gheebati Wal-bid’ati Wan-nameemati Wal-fawahishi Wal-buhtaani Wal-m’aasi Kulli-haa\n"
        "Wa-Aslamtu Wa-aqoolu Laaa Ilaaha Illa-llaahu Muhammadu-r Rasoolu-llah\n"
    </string>


</resources>
